[
  {
    "question": "Pollination by ______ is more common amongst abiotic pollinations.",
    "answer": "wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wind pollination requires that the pollen grains are light and ______ so that they can be transported in wind currents.",
    "answer": "non-sticky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wind-pollinated flowers often possess well-exposed ______ so that the pollens are easily dispersed into wind currents.",
    "answer": "stamens"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wind-pollinated flowers often have large often-feathery ______ to easily trap air-borne pollen grains.",
    "answer": "stigma"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wind-pollinated flowers often have a single ______ in each ovary.",
    "answer": "ovule"
  },
  {
    "question": "A familiar example of a wind-pollinated inflorescence is the ______ cob.",
    "answer": "corn"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ears of corn are nothing but the stigma and ______ which wave in the wind to trap pollen grains.",
    "answer": "style"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wind-pollination is quite common in ______.",
    "answer": "grasses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pollination by ______ is quite rare in flowering plants.",
    "answer": "water"
  },
  {
    "question": "Water pollination is limited to about ______ genera, mostly monocotyledons.",
    "answer": "30"
  },
  {
    "question": "Water is a regular mode of transport for the male gametes among the lower plant groups such as algae, ______ and pteridophytes.",
    "answer": "bryophytes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some examples of water pollinated plants are Vallisneria and ______ which grow in fresh water.",
    "answer": "Hydrilla"
  },
  {
    "question": "Several marine sea-grasses such as ______ are water pollinated.",
    "answer": "Zostera"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a majority of aquatic plants such as water hyacinth and water lily, the flowers emerge above the level of water and are pollinated by insects or ______.",
    "answer": "wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Vallisneria, the female flower reaches the surface of water by the long ______.",
    "answer": "stalk"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Vallisneria, male flowers or pollen grains are released on to the surface of ______.",
    "answer": "water"
  },
  {
    "question": "In some water pollinated plants, pollen grains are long, ribbon like and are carried passively inside the ______.",
    "answer": "water"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pollen grains in most water-pollinated species are protected from wetting by a ______ covering.",
    "answer": "mucilaginous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Both wind and water pollinated flowers are not very ______ and do not produce nectar.",
    "answer": "colourful"
  }
]
